Steven Bi

Full Stack Developer

Perth WA

steven.bb.0221@gmail.com

+61 450 980 608

I'm a seasoned Full Stack Developer with a strong passion for crafting end-to-end solutions. I am familiar with cloud technologies and have experience working in both development and product environments.

For more details can check my page: https://chen-bbe.github.io/MyPage/

- Strong proficiency in server-side programming using Python and Node.js.
- Extensive expertise in frontend development utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Expertise with popular frameworks like Django, Flask, FastAPI, and Express, alongside frontend frameworks such as React and Vue.
- Familiarity with AWS cloud technologies.
- Hands-on experience in API development.
- Experiences with sql & nosql DB.
- Comfortable working with Git and Docker.
- Familiarity and comfort with Agile Scrum methodologies in team project environments.

Personal Details

Eligible to work in Australia: Yes

Highest Level of Education: Bachelor Degree

Work Experience

Frontend Developer (Contract)

NTT DATA - Perth WA

May 2023 to August 2023

I was a front developer on NTT Data team working on client-side, in charge of client's data visualization & reporting system, and work with senior data engineers to demonstrate fully functional prototypes to stakeholders.

Tech Stack: Python, Dash & Plotly, Flask, React, Azure SQL

- Finished all prototypes with required features and designs.
- Identify and explain the gap between current Power BI system and Dash & Plotly
- Created cache architectural layer for improving heavy load and real-time data visualization.

Full Stack Developer

Pointerra - Perth WA

June 2022 to December 2022

I worked as a full-stack developer at Pointerra, where I was responsible for maintaining both frontend and backend services of the current platform. Additionally, I assisted in migrating the system to AWS.

Tech Stack: Django, Vue, AWS API Gateway, AWS Cognito, AWS Lambda, AWS SQS, AWS Event Bus, AWS SNS. AWS S3 bucket.

- Added walk-through feature to the platform for marketing team, create on-board interactive functionalities for plateform new users.
- Implemented a notification mechanism across different channels to support development team bug fixes, while also keeping platform users updated in real-time.
- Helping deployment process for Pointerra's SaaS applications

Software Developer

Atomorphis (Idoba) - Perth WA November 2020 to June 2022

I was a software developer at Atomorphis (now known as Idoba) and core team member working on an in-house product (Gemini) from scratch. My main responsibility was the implementation of the web application based on clients requirements. Additionally, I collaborated with the CTO to build API layers based on the existing engine and deploy the product.

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Deck.gl, Mapbox, MUI(Material UI), FastAPI, Postgres, Docker, AWS

- Implemented Gemini web based simulation tool, https://static1.squarespace.com/static/640eab33ae82eb7bd001b933/t/653f675c3db52712ca4ee98a/1698654049840/231030-Gemini-2page-Brochure.pdf
- Exploring all possible tech and tools for supporting 2D & 3D in data visualizationa & simulation on web app.
- Played a pivotal role in every step of the product lifecycle.
- Helped product down to the ground and the product acquisition from Idoba.

Software Developer

Lianjia - 卜海市

January 2019 to September 2020

I was a software engineer on "Lianjia" platform team based in shanghai.

Ensure that the platform consistently delivers optimal user experiences across both PC and mobile devices, actively engage in hotfixes within the on-call group, and maintain the stability of the platform's system at all times.

Tech Stack: Python, Node.js, React, Alibaba Coud

- Accomplished the transition from a junior to a mid-level software developer role
- · Earning rewards of both full-attendance bonus and outstanding performance

Education

Bachelor of Science (Computing) in Software Engineering

Curtin University - Perth WA

August 2014 to December 2018

Skills

- CSS
- HTML
- JavaScript

- React
- Redux
- RESTful API
- Python
- Flask
- Django
- Pandas
- NumPy
- Docker
- Git
- AWS
- Agile
- Node.js

Links

http://www.linkedin.com/in/steven-bi-786728a8

https://chen-bbe.github.io/MyPage/

https://github.com/Chen-BBe/

Additional Information

• Language: Mandarin and English